## Daniel Kuhman

# Analytics & Data Science

I am a trained research scientist with 9 years of experience in analytics and data science across a variety of fields. I bring the passion and expertise needed to help businesses derive meaningful and actionable insights from their data. Let's build something cool together!

danielkuhman@gmail.com · LinkedIn · GitHub · Website · Publications

### Experience

#### Strike (Zap Solutions Inc.) / Data Analyst

April 2022 - June 2023, Remote

I worked cross-functionally with multiple teams throughout the organization, using data to help guide business decisions and to help develop and implement in-app features.

#### City Enterprises / Director of Data Science

April 2021 - April 2022, Murfreesboro TN

I implemented data-driven approaches to inventory optimization for multiple car lots and developed ML models to guide vehicle acquisition. I also helped develop, track, and forecast KPIs related to vehicle sales.

#### University of Alabama Birmingham / Research Fellow

August 2017 - April 2021, Birmingham AL

I worked in the UAB Biomechanics Lab while completing my doctoral studies and dissertation. I collected and processed data, conducted statistical analysis on large, complex data sets, and presented and published findings.

#### East Carolina University / Graduate Research & Teaching Assistant

August 2015 - May 2017, Greenville NC

I worked in the ECU Biomechanics Lab while completing my masters studies and thesis. I collected and processed data, conducted statistical analysis on large, complex data sets, and published findings.

#### University of Memphis / Undergraduate Research Assistant

June 2014 - May 2015, Memphis TN

I aided in data collection and analysis in the Musculoskeletal Dynamics Lab and the Cardiorespiratory & Metabolic Lab as an undergraduate student.

#### **Education**

#### **Google Career Certificates**

- Data Analytics: Completed on Coursera, August 2023
- Business Intelligence: Completed on Coursera, September 2023

#### University of Alabama Birmingham / Ph.D. Rehabilitation Science

August 2017 - August 2021, With dissertation, GPA: 4.0

#### East Carolina University / M.S. Biomechanics

August 2015 - May 2017, With thesis, GPA: 4.0

#### University of Memphis / B.S.Ed. Health & Human Performance

August 2011 - May 2015, GPA: 3.8, Suma Cum Laude, Honors

#### **Relevant Skills**

- Languages: SQL, R, Python
- Git, Google Cloud Platform, BigQuery, Airflow, dbt
- BI Tools: Looker, Cluvio, Tableau, Google Analytics
- Written and verbal communication
- Self-starter, independent, fast learner, motivated